Bharat Singh

Email: bksingh@g.cofc.edu

GitHub Link: https://github.com/bksinn

Portfolio link: https://bksinn.github.io

Colonial Life

1200 Colonial Life Blvd W

Columbia, SC 29210

To Colonial Life:

This letter is to express my interest in the Front End Developer I position at Colonial Life. After looking at the website and reading the position description, I believe I would mesh well with both the development team and the company culture.

Although I began my career as a chemist, I've also worked in a medical clinic that treated hundreds of patients for all sorts of complexes, and worked as an analyst on a small IT team that was tasked with process improvement for a business—the work we did affected areas of this business across the board. I have had a considerable amount of experience learning challenging material and needing to account for very specific, high levels of detail in my work environment.

I am currently attending The Iron Yard's Front End Engineering course and am looking forward to the next development project I can contribute to. After my experience with working on a small IT team, deciding to attend a fully immersive course that teaches code was the next organic move, and I now have foundational knowledge in the most widely used web technologies and their respective frameworks (i.e. HTML, CSS, Javascript, React.js). The relevance of technology and its potential to continue improving people's standard of living is what drove me to this field, and being able to contribute on an impassioned level is what I have to offer Colonial Life.

Thank you for the consideration,

Bharat K. Singh

BHARAT K. SINGH

(803) 747-0640 | bksingh@g.cofc.edu| GitHub: https://github.com/bksinn | Portfolio: https://bksinn.github.io LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bharat-singh-31881089

EDUCATION:

Front End Engineering, The Iron Yard Academy

Complete Date: May 2017

Full immersive accelerator program with a focus on modern web technologies and industry best practices

B.A. Chemistry, College of Charleston

Complete Date: May 2013

SKILLS: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JS ES6, Sass, Git, Github, React.js, Responsive Web Design, Titration, Instrument Spectroscopy, Chemical synthesis, Quantitative analysis, Management, Data analysis, Data mining

EXPERIENCE:

The Melrose Community Health Clinic- Los Angeles, CA **Director of Laboratory Services**

January 2015-June 2016

- Primary liaison between both Chief Medical Officer, Chief Executive Officer and third party toxicology labs being used
- Directed, established, and planned overall policies and goals for both clinic's and rehabilitation center's laboratory services (primarily urinary drug tests)
- Worked closely with operations staff, department directors, and physicians to ensure highest standards of quality and service were maintained
- Trained various facilities on operating protocol for specimen collection throughout LA county and Denver, CO areas
- Systemized collection and test ordering process for drug testing across facilities company-wide
- Developed knowledge of Kareo's Electronic Health Record and Kareo's Practice Management systems
- Working knowledge of various laboratory information systems
- Coordinated closely with Insurance Department to create a more integrated billing and tracking system for the increased volume of patient specimens

The Los Angeles Family Institute- Los Angeles, CA **Systems Analyst**

January 2014-December 2014

- Stems Analyst
 - Examined new and existing information systems in order to implement, configure, and test feasible solutions
 - Worked closely with both the Management Information Systems and IT departments
- Created an integrated approach to improving general company metrics
- Maintained various company data across all departments to assess efficacy of client care
- Wrote business plan for company's migration to a relational database management system

BASF- Spartanburg, SC **Quality Control Chemist**

August 2013-December 2013

- Performed a variety of quality control test measures to ensure integrity of chemicals made on-site
- Analyzed initial and finished stages of surfactants (polymers and polyethers)
- Approved shipments, finished products, and gave in-process approval for products during various stages of their development
- Communicated with the control room, engineers, and chemical operators when products' specifications were out of range (required to calculate corrective measures and report back to engineers)